Justin Heath

Full-Stack Developer

Professional Statement

Technically proficient software engineer focused on creating meaningful UI experiences backed up with latest methods for efficiency and storing data of the highest quality. Over 6 year's experience of working with stakeholders, developing innovative solutions to produce absorbing content whilst maintaining a concrete relationship.

With a constant desire to simplify the process to complete a given task, I have cultivated a knowledge of best practices for most scenarios and often receive positive feedback from users on my work. I enjoy how full-stack development gives me the skills to rapidly go from 'discussion' to 'concept' to 'refactoring', as my knowledge grows this becomes even more enjoyable.

"Working with Justin on projects is always a productive time where his years of experience and clinical approach, reduces the bottlenecks I am used to encountering."

Taso Gazis Diabetes & Endocrinology consultant @ NUH

Wanting to further deepen my expertise as a software engineer, I would relish the opportunity to develop a knowledge of wireframing and cloud-based platforms. I know my values and commitment are a perfect accompaniment to any organisation and I look forward to growing together.

Recent Projects

Networking, Opensource and Mentoring

I am working with 2 industry-based mentors to help guide me through my journey of up skilling in line with what is sort after in industry. Complementing this with weekly networking and attending meetup's that I enjoy learning from and occasionally contributing to, I am looking forward to attending my 1st hackathon. Recently started to contribute to 'opensource' projects which I feel also helps me learn and develop in a way that is relevant and in line with best practices (OS projects = 'up-for-grabs.net' and 'openmrs').

Nottinghamshire COVID Vaccination Programme

Designed the UI and SQL tables for the creation of cohort patients lists to be contact for the C19 vaccine. Anticipating this would be ever-evolving facility I future proofed it to generate different cohorts as they were nationally decided (i.e. 80+, 75-80, etc..). Designed and built in 2 days, pulling on my knowledge of the data and my skills in HTML, CSS and SQL.

COVID Staffing and PPE Register

Design the UI and SQL tables for primary care to record staffing and PPE levels which was then exported to csv for a national submission. Designed and built in 2 weeks, pulling on previous experience I was able to provide a snapshot summary with the ability to drill down if required to more granular data.

Mailing and Newsletter System

Created the ability to send out individual correspondences or a regional newsletter to all staff or a limited cohort of staff. Data validation was key here to ensure it would process through the NHS mailing system. Gaining experience in embedding text editors into the webpage to format the final mail in HTML and CSS. Created all the UI and tables used to store the data, this was a massive project that I enjoyed doing a lot. It took about 6 months with many challenges and skills developed along the way.

Relevant Experience

Software Engineer - Nottingham & Nottinghamshire CCG - 2017 — Present **Company Description** – Control the funding for all healthcare in Nottinghamshire.

- UI development utilising HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
 Support all data imports into the data warehouse using Visual Studio Suite.
- · Building tables and views in SQL, updating data with T-SQL in SP's & agent jobs.

Senior Accountant - Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust - 2015 — 2017

Company Description – Primary acute healthcare provider in Leeds.

- Led on the theatres paperless/automated stocking system and data loads. Led the consultant engagement scheme in line with the trusts core values.
- · Supported the wider accounts dept to deliver/understand costing data.

Accountant - Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust - 2007 - 2014

Company Description – *Primary acute healthcare provider in Nottingham.*

- Managed the transformation of the cashiers dept to paperless.
 Equipped 50 colleagues in management accounts with paperless data entry.
- · Built BI platform of financial information used by all stakeholders within trust & is now used nationally.

CONTACT

justin@justcoder.fun 07941 539 609

Skills

HTML & CSS

4 vears

Javascript (ES6, Node.js, React.js, JQuery)

1 year

Bootstrap & SASS

1 year

SQL (SQL Server, T-SQL and PostgreSQL)

VBA & C# (in excel mainly VBA)

10 years

Visual Studio Suite (SSAS, SSRS, SSIS)

4 years

Git and Github

1 year

Healthcare Costing Accountant (Qlikview)

Communication & Engagement

15 years

Education

Purple Beard Training

Coding Boot Camp (2021 Jan - Mar) w3school Front-End Certificate

Kaplan Online

Accounting AAT (2010 - 2014) Level 2,3 & 4

Derby University

A Levels (2001 - 2003)

Maths, Physics & Computer Science

Interests

Volunteering in the 'Canal Trust' Walking and Running Researching & Learning Technologies Network with 'TechNotts' & 'York Dev' Attend MeetUps for the Tech Community

Reference

Omitted from Online Version